A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- General Files, 1959
  - Jefferson Bicentennial--Alvin Barkley Speech 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Law Department (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Lectures--Religion 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Lectures--Page-Barbour 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Legal Matters (W. A. Perkins, atty) 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Library (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - McIntire Fund 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - McGregor Library 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Library--Taylor Room 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Madison Hall 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Mary Washington College 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Mathematics 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Hospital 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Medical Department--Ward Patients 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Medical Department--Student Health 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Military Government, School of 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Museum of Science 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Music 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - National Association of State Universities 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Noell Bill 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Personnel 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Personnel--Retirement Plan 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Philosophy 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Physics 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Political Science 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Post-War Education Committee (not local) 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Post-War University (College) Committee Reports 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Psychology 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Public Administration--Bureau of (includes Annual Report) 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Public Speaking 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Publicity 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Questionnaires 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Religion 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Requisitions 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Research--League of Virginia Counties--County Government Clinic 1943-1944 (Box 10)
  - Romance Languages 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Rural Social Economics (Fulmer, John L.) 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - "S" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Senate (Minutes) 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Sigma Xi 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Sociology 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - State Board of Education 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Statistics 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Stettinius, Edward 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Summer Session 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Surplus Property 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Taylor, Mrs. R. C. 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Town Meeting of the Air 1943-1944 (Box 11)
  - Tunstall, Robert B. 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - University in the War 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Veterans Administration 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Visitors--Correspondence (2 folders) 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Visitors--Dockets, Minutes, and Memorandum 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Women, Dean of 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1943-1944 (Box 12)
  - SUB-SERIES II: General Files, 1945
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office 1945 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office--Alumni Fund, Class Managers, Bulletin 1945 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office--Alumni Fund--Council 1945 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office--Alumni Fund--Gifts 1945 (Box 13)
  - Annual Reports 1945 (Box 13)
  - Applications for Positions 1945 (Box 13)
  - Art and Architecture 1945 (Box 13)
  - Art Commission 1945 (Box 13)
  - Association of American Colleges 1945 (Box 13)
  - Association of American Universities 1945 (Box 13)
  - Astronomy 1945 (Box 13)
  - Athletics 1945 (Box 13)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 13)
  - Biblical History and Literature 1945 (Box 13)
  - Biology 1945 (Box 13)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm (contains a history of the farm) 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General--Cemeteries 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General--Commons 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing--General 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Emergency Housing--Federal Public Housing 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Fraternity Houses 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Fuel 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Hospital 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Naval Housing 1945 (Box 13)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Sewage Disposal 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--General 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Cafeteria and Dining Hall 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Contracts 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Mary Washington Building 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Medical Buildings 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Men's Dormitories 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Natural Resources Building 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Naval Armory 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Nurses Home 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Rotunda Restoration 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Site Plans 1945 (Box 13)
  - Building Program--Student Activities Building 1945 (Box 15)
  - Building Program--Women's Dormitory 1945 (Box 15)
  - Bursar's Office--General (contains annual report) 1945 (Box 15)
  - Bursar's Office--Fellowships and Student Assistantships 1945 (Box 15)
  - Byrd, Senator H. F. 1945 (Box 15)
  - "C" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 15)
  - Catalogues 1945 (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation for the Advancement of Teaching--General Correspondence 1945 (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation for the Advancement of Teaching--Minutes of Meeting 1945 (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1945 (Box 15)
  - Chemistry Department 1945 (Box 15)
  - Church Society for College Work 1945 (Box 15)
  - Committee--Local Building 1945 (Box 15)
  - Committee--Medical School and Hospital 1945 (Box 15)
  - Committee--Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 15)
  - Committee--New Buildings 1945 (Box 15)
  - Committee--University of VA Press 1945 (Box 15)
  - Commons (contains Navy material) 1945 (Box 15)
  - Conservation Commission (information re--new natural resources building to be built at U.Va. and to house the Forest Service and the Geological Survey) 1945 (Box 15)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 15)
  - Darden, C. W. 1945 (Box 15)
  - Dean Ferguson (reorganization of school since Military departed) 1945 (Box 15)
  - Dean Finley 1945 (Box 15)
  - Dean Lewis 1945 (Box 15)
  - Dean Manahan 1945 (Box 15)
  - Dean Newman 1945 (Box 16)
  - Dean of Women (attempts to have age limit for admissions changed) 1945 (Box 16)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 16)
  - Economics 1945 (Box 16)
  - Education--General 1945 (Box 16)
  - Education--Graduate (Endowment) 1945 (Box 16)
  - Education--Graduate (Denny School) 1945 (Box 16)
  - Education--Nursing 1945 (Box 16)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board--Contingent Fund 1945 (Box 16)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board--General Correspondence 1945 (Box 16)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board--Investments 1945 (Box 16)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board--Meetings 1945 (Box 16)
  - Endowment--Alumni Board--Treasurer 1945 (Box 16)
  - Engineering 1945 (Box 16)
  - English--Lyndon Kent School of English Literature 1945 (Box 16)
  - English--Poe School of English 1945 (Box 16)
  - Extension Department 1945 (Box 16)
  - Extension Division--Radio Uses 1945 (Box 16)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 16)
  - Faculty 1945 (Box 16)
  - Faculty--Instructors and Assistants 1945 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--General 1945 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Rhodes 1945 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--William A. Smith Memorial Scholarships 1945 (Box 16)
  - Finals 1945 (Box 16)
  - Foreign Affairs (material concerning opening of school of foreign affairs) 1945 (Box 17)
  - Forestry (Seward Forest) 1945 (Box 17)
  - Forms and Form Letters 1945 (Box 17)
  - Founder's Day 1945 (Box 17)
  - Fraternities 1945 (Box 17)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 17)
  - General Education Board (discussion of desegregation of police force) 1945 (Box 17)
  - Geography (dept. established) 1945 (Box 17)
  - Geology 1945 (Box 17)
  - Geological Survey 1945 (Box 17)
  - Germanic Languages 1945 (Box 17)
  - Gifts to the University 1945 (Box 17)
  - Governor's Office 1945 (Box 17)
  - Graduate Dept. 1945 (Box 17)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 17)
  - History 1945 (Box 17)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 17)
  - Institute of International Education 1945 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1945 (Box 17)
  - Insurance--TIAA and Blue Cross 1945 (Box 17)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 17)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1945 (Box 17)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation--Park Commission 1945 (Box 17)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 18)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 18)
  - Law Department (discussion of needs include library, housing, a Professor of International Law, Legal Medicine course) 1945 (Box 18)
  - Legal Matters 1945 (Box 18)
  - Library--General 1945 (Box 18)
  - Library--Board of Alderman 1945 (Box 18)
  - Library--McGregor Library 1945 (Box 18)
  - Library--Taylor Room (building of room) 1945 (Box 18)
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 18)
  - McIntire Fund 1945 (Box 18)
  - Madison Hall 1945 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington 1945 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington Dockets 1945 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington Reports 1945 (Box 18)
  - Medical Department--Hospital 1945 (Box 18)
  - Medical Department--Medical Compensation 1945 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Medical Compensation--Copies of Papers 1945 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Medical School 1945 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--School of Nursing 1945 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Student Health 1945 (Box 19)
  - Medical Department--Ward Patient Reports 1945 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities 1945 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities--Committee on Accrediting 1945 (Box 19)
  - National Education Association 1945 (Box 19)
  - Naval ROTC 1945 (Box 19)
  - Naval ROTC--printed and mimeographed communications 1945 (Box 19)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 19)
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 19)
  - Patent Infringements 1945 (Box 19)
  - Personnel 1945 (Box 19)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1945 (Box 19)
  - Philosophy 1945 (Box 19)
  - Physical Education 1945 (Box 19)
  - Physics 1945 (Box 19)
  - Political Science 1945 (Box 20)
  - Post-War Education Committee 1945 (Box 20)
  - Psychology 1945 (Box 20)
  - Publications and Clippings 1945 (Box 20)
  - Public Speaking 1945 (Box 20)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 20)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 20)
  - Radio Committee 1945 (Box 20)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1945 (Box 20)
  - Rent Control 1945 (Box 20)
  - Requisitions 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--General 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Bureau of Population and Economic Research (Miscellaneous printed bulletins) 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Bureau of Administration 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Bureau of Administration (printed reports, etc.) 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--League of Virginia Counties 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1945 (Box 20)
  - Research--Richmond University Center 1945 (Box 20)
  - Romance Languages 1945 (Box 20)
  - Rural Social Economics 1945 (Box 21)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - Scholarships (see Fellowships and Scholarships) 1945 (Box 21)
  - Sigma Xi 1945 (Box 21)
  - Sociology 1945 (Box 21)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1945 (Box 21)
  - Southern University Conference 1945 (Box 21)
  - State Board of Education 1945 (Box 21)
  - Statistics 1945 (Box 21)
  - Summer Session 1945 (Box 21)
  - Surplus Property 1945 (Box 21)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - Taylor, Mrs. R. C. 1945 (Box 21)
  - Tunstall, R. B. 1945 (Box 21)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - United States Office of Education 1945 (Box 21)
  - University in the War (letters from Alumni and State members) 1945 (Box 21)
  - University Houses--Applications for 1945 (Box 21)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - Veterans 1945 (Box 21)
  - Veterans (printed and mimeographed material) 1945 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Education Association 1945 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1945 (Box 21)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Correspondence 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Anderson 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Black 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Senator Bustard 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Calcott 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Carrington 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Corbitt 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Dr. Emmett 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Garnett 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Goolrick 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Laneaster 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Stettinius 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Dr. Trout 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Wailes 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. Lewis C. Williams 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mr. R. Gray Williams 1945 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Mrs. Willis 1945 (Box 21)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1945 (Box 21)
  - "X-Y" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)
  - "Z" Miscellaneous 1945 (Box 21)